Let the love, murder and conspiracy begin.
Amsterdam is a mystery, comedy, drama film directed by David O. Russell.
In the 1930s, three friends—a doctor, a nurse, and an attorney—witness a murder, become
suspects themselves and uncover one of the most outrageous plots in American history.
Burt Berendsen, played by Christian Bale.
Valerie Voze, played by Margot Robbie.
Harold Woodman, played by John David Washington.
Detective Hiltz, played by Alessandro Nivola.
Beatrice Vandenheuvel, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Libby Voze, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Amsterdam is a 2022 mystery comedy thriller film
produced, written, and directed by David O.
It stars Christian Bale (also a producer), Margot Robbie, and John
David Washington, alongside an ensemble supporting cast.
Based on the Business Plot, a 1933 political conspiracy in the US, it follows three friends—a doctor, a nurse, and
a lawyer—who reunite and seek to uncover the act following the mysterious murder of a retired U.S.
Filmed in Los Angeles from January to March 2021, it is
Russell's first film since Joy (2015).
Amsterdam premiered at the Alice Tully Hall on September 18, 2022, and was released
theatrically in the United States on October 7 by 20th Century Studios.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, who criticized Russell's screenplay
and direction, as well as the lack of chemistry between Robbie and Washington.
It was also a box-office bomb, with estimated losses
for the studio of over $100 million.
The film explores themes of investigation, secret
organization, based on true story, conspiracy, racism.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.